Gral. Pinto 250
Tandil, Bs. As., Argentina

⑤ +54 2262 541603

⋈ ezequielscott@gmail.com
Google Scholar Profile

Ezequiel Scott

Research Interests

My research interests lie at the intersection between software engineering and education, mainly focusing on adaptive environments for aiding students in their learning process. I have a strong interest in human factors and psychological issues involved in technology enhanced learning. Moreover, I have most recently focused on applying adaptive environments for teaching agile methods like Scrum.

Education

2012–2016 **Ph.D. in Computer Science**, *Universidad Nacional del Centro de la Provincia de Buenos Aires (UNICEN)*, Tandil, Argentina.

2006–2012 **Systems Engineer**, *Universidad Nacional del Centro de la Provincia de Buenos Aires (UNICEN)*, Tandil, Argentina.

Ph.D. Thesis

Title An Adaptive Approach for Training Software Developers

Supervisors Advisor: Dr. Marcelo Campo; Co-Advisor: Dr. Álvaro Soria

Description This thesis explored the idea that Adaptive Virtual Learning Environments are usefull tools for training developers in Scrum. I found that adapting the environment according to the developer's learning style improves their understanding and performance in Scrum.

Teaching Experience

October **Teaching Assistant**, *Faculty of Exact Sciences, UNICEN*, Tandil, Argentina. 2016–Present Graduate Teaching Assistant in the course "Documentation and Validation Techniques" at UNICEN.

April **Teaching Assistant**, Faculty of Exact Sciences, UNICEN, Tandil, Argentina. 2015–October Graduate Teaching Assistant in the course "Software Engineering" at UNICEN. Research activities involved.

October **Teaching Assistant**, Faculty of Exact Sciences, UNICEN, Tandil, Argentina. 2012–April 2015 Graduate Teaching Assistant Ad-Honorem in the course "Software Engineering Workshop" at UNICEN. Research activities involved.

April **Teaching Assistant**, Faculty of Exact Sciences, UNICEN, Tandil, Argentina. 2014–October Graduate Teaching Assistant in the course "Software Engineering" at UNICEN. Research activities involved.

April 2013–October 2013 **Teaching Assistant**, Faculty of Exact Sciences, UNICEN, Tandil, Argentina. Graduate Teaching Assistant in the course "Object Oriented Programming" at UNICEN.

Supervised Projects

2016 Co-advisor of the final project entitled "A Virtual Environment for Teaching Scrum with LEGO" (undergraduate level).

Professional Experience

2011–2012 **Support and Development**, *Geneos*, Tandil, Argentina.

In this job, I was responsible for supporting the environment and tools for carrying out the organizational processes successfully. The main tool used to manage the processes was the Open Source ERP+CRM Compiere. Additionally, I was responsible for developing new extensions and adapting previous functionality.

Languages

Spanish Mother tongue

English Intermediate Degree obtained as a requirement for the UNICEN Ph.D program.

French Basic A2 Diplôme d'études en langue française DELF A1 – Ministère de

L'éducation Nationale, de L'enseignement Supérieur et de la Recherche, République Française.

German Elementary

Skills

Software Empirical Software Engineering, Planning and Estimation, Process mining,

Engineering Measurement and Analysis, CMMi, Scrum, Systematic Literature Reviews

Quantitative Meta analysis, Educational Experimental Designs, Psychometric Measurement,

Analysis Questionnaire Development and Analysis

Datamining Weka, Knime, Rapidminer, ProM

Tools

Frameworks Unity3D, Smartfox, Yii, Eclipse, Qt

Programming JAVA, Javascript, HTML, PHP, C/C++, C#

Scientific R project, Gnuplot, SPSS, LATEX

Publications

International Journals

2016 Ezequiel Scott, Álvaro Soria, and Marcelo Campo: *Adaptive 3D Virtual Learning Environments – A Review of the Literature.* IEEE Transactions on Learning Technologies; 09/2016 [In press]; IEEE. DOI: 10.1109/TLT.2016.2609910

Ezequiel Scott, Álvaro Soria, and Marcelo Campo: *A taxonomy-based approach for fault localization in Service-Oriented applications*. IEEE Latin America Transactions 14:5; 05/2016; 2348–2354. IEEE. DOI: 10.1109/TLA.2016.7530432

- Ezequiel Scott, Guillermo Rodríguez, Álvaro Soria, Marcelo Campo: *Towards better Scrum learning using learning styles*. Journal of Systems and Software. 01/2016; 242–253. Elsevier. DOI: 10.1016/j.jss.2015.10.022
- 2014 Ezequiel Scott, Guillermo Rodríguez, Álvaro Soria, Marcelo Campo: Are learning styles useful indicators to discover how students use Scrum for the first time? Computers in Human Behavior 07/2014; 36:56–64. Elsevier. DOI: 10.1016/j.chb.2014.03.027

Book Chapters

2014 Ezequiel Scott, Guillermo Rodríguez, Álvaro Soria, Marcelo Campo: Experiences in Software Engineering Education: Using Scrum, Agile Coaching, and Virtual Reality. Overcoming Challenges in Software Engineering Education: Delivering Non-Technical Knowledge and Skills, Edited by Liguo Yu, 01/2014: chapter Experiences in Software Engineering Education: Using Scrum, Agile Coaching, and Virtual Reality: pages 250-276; IGI Global., ISBN: 1466658010

Conferences

- 2016 Ezequiel Scott, Guillermo Rodríguez, Álvaro Soria, Marcelo Campo: Towards better Scrum learning using learning styles. In Communications of XV Argentine Symposium on Software Engineering (ASSE) - 45 JAIIO. Buenos Aires, Argentina; 09/2016.
- Ezequiel Scott, Guillermo Rodríguez, Álvaro Soria, Marcelo Campo: Are learning styles useful indicators to discover how students use Scrum for the first time?.
 In Communications of XV Argentine Symposium on Artificial Intelligence (ASAI)
 44 JAIIO. Buenos Aires, Argentina; 09/2015.
- 2014 Guillermo Rodríguez, Ezequiel Scott, Álvaro Soria, Marcelo Campo: Razon-amiento basado en casos para la materialización de arquitecturas orientadas a servicios. In XV Argentine Symposium on Artificial Intelligence (ASAI) 43 JAIIO. Buenos Aires, Argentina; 09/2014.
- 2013 Ezequiel Scott, Guillermo Rodríguez, Álvaro Soria, Marcelo Campo: El Rol del Estilo de Aprendizaje en la Enseñanza de Prácticas de Scrum: Un Enfoque Estadístico. In Argentine Symposium on Software Engineering (ASSE) 42 JAIIO. Córdoba, Argentina; 09/2013.
- 2012 Ezequiel Scott, Álvaro Soria: Localización de Fallas dirigida por Taxonomía en Aplicaciones Orientadas a Servicios. In Concurso de Trabajos Estudiantiles (EST) - 41 JAIIO. La Plata, Argentina; 08/2012.

Posters

2016 An Adaptive Approach for Training Software Developers presented at 3rd ICSE 2017 PhD and Young Researchers Warm Up Symposium.

Collaboration in Research Projects

2015–2017 Arquitectures, scalable and personalizing techniques for hybrid software systems. Program for Encouraging Teaching and Research. SPU. Code: 03/C258. Director: Dr. Andrés Díaz-Pace.

- 2012–2014 Intelligent assistance of users in desktop, web and mobile applications. Program for Encouraging Teaching and Research. SPU. Code: 03/C237. Director: Dr. Alfredo Teyseyre.
- Visoft-Sur: Software Visualization for assisting software engineers in the development process. Cooperation program between Ministerio de Ciencia, Tecnología e Innovación Productiva de la República Argentina (MINCYT) and Coordinación de Perfeccionamiento del Personal de Nivel Superior (CAPES-Brasil).

Postgraduate Courses

- o Service Oriented Computing at Faculty of Exact Sciences, UNICEN
- Introduction to Evolutionary Computing at Faculty of Exact Sciences, UNI-CEN
- o Advanced Separation of Concerns at Faculty of Exact Sciences, UNICEN
- o Introduction to Mobile Programming at Faculty of Exact Sciences, UNICEN
- Web Data Mining at Faculty of Exact Sciences, UNICEN
- Webtools: tools for the development of Internet applications, e-commerce, and mobile computing at Faculty of Exact Sciences, UNICEN
- Epistemology and Methodology of Science at Faculty of Exact Sciences, UNICEN
- o Introduction to Planning Algorithms at Faculty of Exact Sciences, UNICEN
- o Statistical tools for Researching at Faculty of Exact Sciences, UNICEN

Awards

Doctoral scholarship

Granted by National Council of Scientific and Technical Research (CONICET) since 2012.